medem.com 2013-08-06

# Intuit Health Privacy Statement for Providers

At Intuit, we place the highest importance on respecting and protecting your privacy. Our most important asset is our relationship with you. We want you to feel comfortable and confident when using our Web site. We would like to share with you information on our privacy practices and other privacy aspects of our site. Specifically, we address:

  1. To what products or services does this privacy statement apply?
  2. How do we protect your personal information?
  3. What information do we collect and how do we use it?
  4. When do we share your information?
  5. Can I opt-out of receiving future communications?
  6. How do I update my contact information?
  7. Will I be notified of changes to your privacy practices?
  8. Who can I contact with a privacy question?

## To what products or services does this privacy statement apply?

This privacy statement applies to you as a healthcare provider when you sign up for our Intuit Health Bill Pay Premier or Patient Portal services. Throughout this statement, we refer to information that personally identifies you as "personal information." This privacy statement does not apply to Intuit's practices in handling patient data, which are governed in part by the Business Associate Agreement in place.

## How do we protect your personal information?

We work to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration by using industry-recognized security safeguards that meet or exceed federal requirements. We maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative security standards and procedures to safeguard our data systems. For example, when you transmit sensitive information to us, such as payment information, it is protected by:

  * A secure Internet connection using secure socket layer (SSL) technology.

  * Encryption during transmission to make your information unreadable as it passes over the Internet.

We also educate our employees on the importance of our privacy and security policies, and we require that they comply with those policies.

[Tell me more](https://support.patientpayments.healthcare.intuit.com/cgi-bin/intuitpatientpayments.cfg/php/enduser/std_adp.php?p_faqid=1226&p_sid=mXyPsqqk&p_lva=838&p_accessibility=&p_redirect=&p_srch=&p_sp=cF9zcmNoPSZwX3NvcnRfYnk9JnBfZ3JpZHNvcnQ9JnBfcm93X2NudD02MSw2MSZwX3Byb2RzPSZwX2NhdHM9JnBfcHY9JnBfY3Y9JnBfc2VhcmNoX3R5cGU9YW5zd2Vycy5zZWFyY2hfbmwmcF9wYWdlPTE%21&p_li= "Intuit's security practices") about Intuit Health's security practices.

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

During the course of our relationship with you, we may collect the following types of information:

  * **Contact Information.** We may ask for your contact information, such as your email address and phone number. We use this information to contact you about your services. We may also use it to send you personalized promotional or marketing communications. **If you prefer not to receive promotional or marketing communications** , please email us at [intuithealth@intuit.com](mailto:intuithealth@intuit.com) with "unsubscribe" in the subject line.

If you request customer or technical support, we may use your contact information to elicit your feedback regarding your support experience.

  * **Logon Credentials.** When you open an account with Intuit Health Bill Pay Premier or Intuit Health Patient Portal, we set up a user name and password on your behalf so that you can control access to your account. You can change your logon credentials at any time through the applicable web site.

  * **Healthcare and Healthcare Payment Information.** When you sign up for Intuit Health Patient Portal and/or Intuit Health Bill Pay Premier services, we accept that healthcare and healthcare billing information as you request. In these cases, we become a Business Associate to you and Business Associate Agreement terms may apply. We transmit this data using secure socket layer technology, so it is encrypted and unreadable during transmission. We store the data on our secure servers.

When a patient agrees to make a payment to you through one of our services, he or she will also become a customer of the Intuit Health service. We will maintain that customer's health care data on his or her behalf from that point forward, and the customer will maintain access to the health care data until he or she asks us to close the account, independent of our relationship with you.

  * **Anonymous and Technical Information.** We use anonymous, aggregate statistical information to help improve our services to you. For example, we review what features are used the most frequently, how many total customers may be viewing their information or what types of data are most commonly entered. Statistics like these help us to understand how our services are being used, what user trends may be and how to improve our service in future versions. This anonymous, aggregate information also assists us with troubleshooting and technical support.

We may collect anonymous technical information, such as the software or browser version, or operating system. We may also collect the IP address of the computer used to access our site. To help us evaluate Web site usage, we also collect anonymous information about the pages viewed and links selected by users while using our Web sites. This information helps us to determine areas of our sites that are most helpful to our users and what areas may need improvement. We use cookies to help us track site usage. We also use cookies to make your visit to our Web site easier by recognizing you when you return or by customizing your Web site experience.

[Tell me more](https://support.patientpayments.healthcare.intuit.com/cgi-bin/intuitpatientpayments.cfg/php/enduser/std_adp.php?p_faqid=1227&p_sid=mXyPsqqk&p_lva=838&p_accessibility=&p_redirect=&p_srch=&p_sp=cF9zcmNoPSZwX3NvcnRfYnk9JnBfZ3JpZHNvcnQ9JnBfcm93X2NudD02MSw2MSZwX3Byb2RzPSZwX2NhdHM9JnBfcHY9JnBfY3Y9JnBfc2VhcmNoX3R5cGU9YW5zd2Vycy5zZWFyY2hfbmwmcF9wYWdlPTE%21&p_li= "Intuit's Web technologies") about Intuit's Web Technologies.

  * **Business and Account Behavior Information.** We may use information about the business you are in and your activities within your account to communicate with you about products and services we feel may interest you. 

  * **Other Information Sources.** We may use publicly available sources outside of Intuit to verify or supplement the information you give us. For example, we may obtain address updates from the U.S. Postal Service or demographic information from direct marketing companies. We use this data to help us maintain accurate records and to improve the products and services that we deliver to you.

  * **Children.** This Web site is not designed to appeal to children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly request or receive any information from children

  * **Former Customers.** If you are a former customer, we protect your information in the same manner that we treat information about our current customers.

## When do we share your information?

We understand that you are entrusting us with your personal information. **That's why we don't sell, rent, or share any of the personally identifiable information you provide to us with companies outside of Intuit for their own promotional or marketing use.** There are occasions, however, when we must share your information to provide you with the services you requested or for legal reasons. Descriptions of when and with whom we share are provided below.

  * **With Service Providers.** In some cases, we use third party service providers to provide a product you order, to fulfill a service you request, or to market one of our products or services. These service providers act on our behalf. For example, we may use service providers to provide customer support or to host our Web sites. Service providers who host web pages and collect information on our behalf are strictly prohibited from using your information for their own purposes and must comply with Intuit privacy and security policies and the practices outlined in this privacy statement. Our contracts restrict service providers to use the personal information we disclose to them only to provide you the service you have requested.

  * **With Partners.** We have limited relationships with third parties, such as Electronic Medical Record companies and Value Added Resellers, to offer you products or services that we believe you may find beneficial. Some of these are "co-branded" products or services. We clearly identify third party services and sites, so you will know who is receiving your information. When you request any of these third party products or services, you are permitting us to provide your personal information to the third party to fulfill your request.

We may share or sell anonymous, aggregate statistical information with third parties. Aggregate information means that your anonymous information is combined with similar anonymous information from other users such that it no longer reflects or can be used to identify an individual user. For example, we may determine that 90% of our facilitated payments occur within 30 days of invoice. Such non-personal, aggregate information does not include any information that identifies an individual or that can be linked to a person's identity.

We may also offer links to partner or other third party Web sites. We do not control the privacy or security practices used on these sites. Before you provide your personal information to these third parties, we recommend that you review their privacy policies to learn more about how they may use your information.

  * **Within Intuit, including our subsidiaries.** We may share your contact information (name, address, phone number, email address), and the types of Intuit products and services that you have used, among Intuit and our subsidiaries (companies that are part of our corporate family through ownership or control) to provide you with a service or product you have requested. Unless you have asked us not to contact you, we may occasionally use your contact information to update you about new products we believe may interest you. **Intuit does not share personally identifiable health information with subsidiaries.**

  * **Sale of a Business.** Should we sell, merge, or transfer any part of our business, part of the sale may include your personal information. If so, you will have the opportunity to ask not to receive promotional information following any change of control.

  * **For Legal Reasons.** In some cases we may be required to disclose certain information to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities, comply with a legal process, such as a court order, subpoena, search warrant, law enforcement request, or as otherwise permitted by law to comply with legal requirements.

## What choices do I have?

  * **Opt Out of Marketing.** We may use your contact information (email address, phone, or postal address) to tell you about other products we think might interest you. However, if you do not want us to contact you for promotional purposes, you can tell us when you provide the information. You may also opt out at any time by emailing us at [intuithealth@intuit.com](mailto:intuithealth@intuit.com) with "unsubscribe" in the subject line. Your privacy options only apply to marketing contact by email, phone, or postal mail. We may need to communicate with you regarding the usability of your product or critical messages relating to your service or software (such as service messages, subscription renewal notices, critical notices, or legally mandated notices). If you have subscribed to email notifications, alerts, or newsletters you can cancel your subscription by following the instructions provided in each email.
  * **Cancel your Intuit Health Account.** You may cancel your Intuit Health service(s) at any time. It may not be technologically possible to remove from our systems every record of the personal information you provide. The need to back up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means a copy of your personal information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate or remove. Nevertheless, upon receiving your request, personal information stored in Intuit Health will no longer be used or accessible to provide services.

## How do I update my contact information?

You can update or correct your contact information by submitting a support request.

## Will I be notified of changes to your privacy practices?

If we make material changes to any of our privacy policies or practices regarding personal information we will update our statement and post a notice on our site 30 days before they take effect.

## Who can I contact with a privacy question?

If you have privacy-related questions that are not addressed here, please contact the [Privacy Team](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/comments) or write us at: Privacy Team, Intuit Inc, 2800 East Commerce Center Place, Tucson, AZ 85706.

Last updated 02/20/12
